本作品之片源来自互联网，仅供学习、交流之用。请自觉于下载后24小时内删除。任何组织和个人不得用于任何商业用途，否则一切后果请自行承担！如果喜欢本片，请购买正版！
无限监狱
时光宝宝在看着你
紧急情况
越狱囚犯在逃
站住
Halt!
我要告诉这个罪犯
I've got to hand it to this perp.
从没有人能从无限监狱逃出去
No one's broken out of the Infinetentiary before.
他要么是我见过的最勇敢的时间罪犯  要么是最笨的
He's either the bravest time-convict I've ever seen or the dumbest.
我的时之膝盖
My time-knee!
时之该死的
Oh, time-dang it!
-肯定是最笨的  -不许动
- Definitely the dumbest. - Freeze!
你已被时间悖论规避强执特遣队包围了
You're surrounded by the Time Paradox Avoidance Enforcement Squadron.
你所说的一切可以或者已经在未来法庭上用作指控你的不利证据
Anything you say can and already has been used against you in future court.
时候到了  布伦丁  时间轴的结束
This is it, Blendin. End of the timeline.
还有什么话想说吗
Any last words?
我  我  我  我
Uh-uh-uh-uh-uh... I-I-I-I...
我祈求晶球大战
I invoke Globnar!
晶球大战
Globnar!!!
非常好  说出你所指控的姓名和世纪
Very well, speak the name and century of those accused.
毁掉我生活的两个小孩
The two kids that ruined my life,
迪普和梅宝・派恩斯  二十一世纪
Dipper and Mabel Pines, 21st century.
搜 索
实时录像
已定位
晶球大战贡品
如你所愿
So be it.
愿时光宝宝怜悯他们的灵魂
May Time Baby have mercy on their souls.
■
本字幕由★迪幻字幕组★为您奉献
欢迎登录www.Deefun.com
■
时间轴： WaitinZ
翻译： 发条猫  阿拱  violin1443
■
校订  后期： Enpistu  WaitinZ
怪诞小镇  第二季第八集
Gravity Falls  S02E08  Blendin's Game
糖果  糖果  糖果  糖果
Candy! Candy! Candy! Candy.
糖果  糖果
Candy-- Candy--
不  它被卡住了
No! It's trapped!
一切都永远不如意
Everything is terrible forever!
嗨  伙计们
Psst. Hey, dudes.
想学个花招吗
You want to know a trick?
一个天才教我的
A genius taught me that once.
插播消息  气象站正在召唤一场糖果暴风雪
This just in. Weather stations are calling for a candy blizzard!
忘掉打开包装吧
Forget taking off the wrappers.
我现在就要把它们吃掉
I'm eating these now!
苏斯  你是有史以来最伟大的人
Soos, you are the greatest human ever to live.
这是个错误
That was a mistake!
这没什么  哥们儿
Hey, no sweat, dude.
我愿意为派恩斯家做任何事
I'd do anything for the Pines family.
苏斯
Soos!
我要同时给两个部位挠痒痒
I need to scratch myself in two places at once.
我是说  任何事
And I mean  <i>anything.</i>
来了  派恩斯先生
Coming, Mr. Pines!
最好让他把钱包拿走
Whoa, better make sure he gets his wallet back.
等等  我还从来没见过苏斯的钱包
Wait, I've never seen Soos's wallet before.
你不想知道些苏斯的秘密吗
Don't you want to learn some Soos secrets?
我不知道是否我们应该
I don't know if we should be-- Whoa!
苏斯是激光枪战的会员
Soos has a membership to laser tag?
适合十二岁以下
儿童玩耍
我都不知道他们还允许成年人玩
I didn't know they let grown-ups in there.
看  应急意大利香肠
And look, emergency salami.
苏斯  我对你的敬意大有增长
Soos, my respect for you has grown.
赫苏斯・埃扎米拉诺・拉米雷斯
Jesus Alzamirano Ramirez,
器官捐献者  生日  七月十三日
organ donor, birthday: July 13th.
等一下
Wait a minute.
就是今天
That's today.
好奇怪
That's weird.
他为什么没告诉其他人呢
I wonder why he didn't tell anyone.
那还用问
Uh, duh.
也许是因为他想让人给他开一个惊喜派对
It's probably because he wants someone to throw him a surprise party.
我这辈子一直都在等惊喜派对
I've been waiting for a surprise party my whole life.
惊喜
Surprise!
有点晚了  秋
Too little, too late, Chiu.
再来点感叹号
More exclamation points!
我说再来点
More, I say!
你们这些家伙真是什么事都想到了
Wow, you guys thought of everything.
格兰达  双胞胎生来就是生日专家
Grenda, twins are born birthday experts.
我们每个生日都一起过
We've shared every birthday together
所以我们知道该怎么让生日变得完美
so we know how to make them perfect.
大家快就位
Hey, places, everyone.
我听见脚步声了
I hear footsteps.
大家安静
Everyone, be quiet!
好吧  你向我保证会有一只大蜂鸟
All right, you promised a giant hummingbird,
那么我就期待看到一只大蜂鸟
so I'm expecting to see a giant hummingbird.
三  二  一
Three, two, one...
惊喜
Surprise!
生日快乐  地球之王
Happy birthday, you king on earth.
我们搞到了所有你喜欢的东西
We got everything you love.
蛋糕味的披萨
Cake-flavored pizza.
披萨味的蛋糕
Pizza-flavored cake.
还有更多乐趣
And one more treat.
眼花缭乱  朋友们
Razzle dazzle, friends.
是我  眼花缭乱男
It's me, the Razz Dazzler.
这就是我现在的生活
This is what my life has become.
我  我
I...I...
快  大家给生日笑容记忆相册摆个姿势
Quick, everyone pose for the Birthday Smiles Memory Album.
苏斯  怎么了
Soos, what's wrong?
没  没什么
It's, uh, it's nothing.
我
I, uh...
我要去修水管什么的了
I gotta go fix a pipe or something.
你们看到苏斯了吗
Whoa, did you guys see Soos?
发生什么了  不
What happened to-- Oh, no.
不  不  不
Oh, no, no, no.
好吧  你们不了解  这不是你们的错
Okay, you guys didn't know, so it's not your fault,
不过  苏斯讨厌他的生日
but Soos hates his birthday.
-什么  -原因谁也不清楚
- What? - It's a total mystery.
我猜他从小时候起就这样了
I guess he's been like this since he was a kid.
奇怪的个人问题
Some weird personal biz.
我们一定能做些什么
There's gotta be something we can do.
我们什么方法都试过了
We've tried everything.
我甚至请求过政府把这天从日历上移除
I even petitioned the government to have this day removed from calendars.
禁乘
航空危险分子
现在都不允许我上飞机了
Now I'm not allowed on airplanes.
来自新奥尔良的问候
我不确定啊  各位
I don't know, guys,
或许我们应该让他一个人待着  你懂吗
maybe we should just leave him alone, you know?
谁都不该在生日的时候孤独一人
No one should be alone on their birthday.
肯定有能让他振奋起来的办法
There's got to be a way to cheer him up.
我们要更努力地试一把
We just need to try harder.
你说的对  迪普
You're right, Dipper!
是时候拿出大家伙了
It's time for us to bring out the big guns.
大家伙激光枪战
好啦  哥们儿
All right, guys,
蒙我眼睛一次你们就已经很可耻了
blindfold me once, shame on you,
蒙我眼睛两次  等一下
blindfold me twice-- Wait a minute.
热狗味
Hot dog smell?
黏胶地板  未来风格的音效
Sticky floors? Future sounds?
激光枪战
Laser tag?
我爱激光枪战  你们怎么知道的
I love laser tag. How'd you guys know?
我们绝对没翻你的钱包
We definitely didn't rifle through your wallet.
欢迎来到8000年
<i>Welcome to the year 8,000.</i>
任务简述
社会  被瓦解了
<i>Society?</i> <i>Collapsed.</i>
烟雾机   到处都是
<i>Fog machines?</i> <i>Everywhere.</i>
这些墙是不是只是喷了紫色漆的床垫
Are these walls just mattresses spray-painted purple?
这地方以前好像是床垫大卖场
I think this place used to be a mattress store.
我不知道  各位
I don't know, guys,
我不确定我今天有兴致玩这个
I'm not sure I'm up for this today.
别担心  苏斯  只要你跟我们玩耍起来
Don't worry, Soos. As soon as you start playing with us,
你会玩得很愉快的
you're gonna have a great time.
我们保证  无论发生什么  我们都不会把你丢在一边
We promise, no matter what happens we won't leave your side.
好吧  我觉得我可以试试
Well, I guess, I could give it a shot.
准备激光战
<i>Prepare for laser battle</i>
三  二
<i>in three, two...</i>
最好把鞋带系上
Better tie down these cowboys.
这比我想象的要酷得多
Whoa! This is even cooler than I imagined.
看这些激光士兵多逼真
Look how real these laser guys are.
踢击防御
<i>Kick deflected.</i>
感谢购买数字编码智能兜裆裤
Thank you for buying digicod, <i>the smart codpiece.</i>
等等  什么
Wait, what?
不
Oh, no.
苏斯
Soos!
梅宝   迪普  伙计们
Mabel? Dipper? Dudes?
苏斯
Soos!
踢得不错  但那是坚固的时间材质  孩子
Nice try, but that's solid timetanium, kid.
只有一个办法从这里出去
There's only one way out of here.
放倒我
Through me!
不好意思
Oh, uh, sorry.
拜托
Come on.
放倒我
Through me!
如果我第一次就能搞对就好了
if I'd just gotten it right the very first chance,
不过效果仍然达到了
but it still is effective.
是那个时间旅行者
The time traveler guy!
你的名字是怎么说来着
What did you say your name was again?
布兰多
Blendo?
布拉丁
Blondin?
布拉布拉
BlarBlar.
对啦
There it is.
是布伦丁
It's Blendin!
布伦丁・布伦杰明・布兰丁
Blendin Blenjamin Blendin.
你们怎么能在毁掉我人生后还不知道我名字呢
How could you not know my name after you ruined my life?!
启动回放
Initiate flashback!
在你们偷走我的时间装备
<i>It was after you stole my time device</i>
去赢回你们的蠢猪后
<i>to win your stupid pig.</i>
我被时光异常校正队赶出来了
<i>I was cast out of the Time Anomaly Removal crew--</i>
那可是我一生的目标啊
my whole life's purpose.
然后我被判处十平方终身监禁
And then I was given
在时光监狱里服刑
<i>ten squared life sentences in time prison.</i>
自那时起  每一天我都在想着如何复仇
I've spent every day since then <i>planning my vengeance.</i>
现在  这个时刻终于到来了
And now finally, it has come!
听着  对于这一切我们很抱歉
Look, we're sorry about all that,
可我们现在正忙着做一件非常重要的事
but we're in the middle of something really important right now.
今天是我们朋友的生日
It's our friend's birthday today,
而且我们说好了不会丢下他
and we promised we wouldn't leave his side.
什么  你们竟然觉得一个愚蠢的生日很重要
What?! You think some dumb birthday matters right now?
你们知道自己现在在哪儿吗
Do you know where you are?
欢迎参加晶球大战
Welcome to Globnar!
这是真人秀吗
<i>Is this a reality show?</i>
我们是在日本吗
<i>Are we in Japan?</i>
这是一个格斗类时间角斗
<i>It's gladiatorial time combat!</i>
获胜者将会得到一个珍贵的时间许愿机会
<i>The winner gets a precious time wish</i>
然后决定失败者的命运
<i>and then decides the loser's fate.</i>
不  求你了
N-n-no! Please!
你们两个正式受到挑战了
And the two of you are officially challenged.
丹格伦
Dundgren!
给我涂战漆
Get me my war paint.
迪普  我们得想办法逃出去
Dipper, we need a way out of here.
可怎么逃呢
But how?
我有个主意
I have an idea.
再坚持一下  苏斯  我们这就去找你
Hang in there, Soos, we're coming for you.
迪普  梅宝
Dipper? Mabel?
请求支援
Requesting back-up.
哦不
Oh, no.
激光战士罗比
Laser Robbie.
伙计们
Dudes?
我的小星星
Oh, my stars.
你是不是我的小  嗯
Could it be my little, um...
小洛菲
Lolphy!
是我啊  我是你的曾曾曾曾曾曾曾祖母
It's me. Your great-great-great-great-great-great-great grandmother
从过去来到这儿的
from the past times.
奶奶
Gam-Gam?
霓虹绿不错
Yeah, neon green is good.
这颜色适合我
This is a good color for me.
看起来很凶猛  对吧
It's fierce-- Huh?
天哪  不
What? No!
别让他们跑了
You can't let them escape!
停下
Stop there!
奶奶  你怎么能这样
Gam-Gam, how could you?
我可不是谁的奶奶  傻瓜
I ain't no one's Gam-Gam, sucka!
你被时间把戏骗到啦
You just got time tricked!
-不  -不
- No! - No!
快  回到苏斯的生日那天
Hurry! Back to Soos' birthday.
好的  我觉得我搞定了
Okay. I think I've got it.
我们回去了吗
Uhh. Are we back?
天哪  快看
Oh, no! Look!
梅宝  激光枪战的位置是个床垫卖场
Mable, the Laser place is a mattress store.
我们穿越过头了
We went too far in the past.
时间旅行
Time travel.
老天  你为什么非得弄得这么复杂
Man, why you gotta be so complicated?
他们好像把目的地时间调早了十年
Looks like they overshot their destination by 10 years.
我没看到他们  你们最好找到那两个小鬼
I don't see them. You better find those kids!
你会得到公正的处置的  布伦丁
You'll get your justice, Blendin.
我会一直结巴  直到你们找到他们
I'm gonna keep stammering until you find them.
我  我  我  我
I-I-I-I...
-我讨厌那个家伙  -咱们走吧
- I hate that guy. - Let's move.
好  我们只要再往后穿十年就行
Okay, we just got to go forward 10 years.
在苏斯发觉我们离开之前赶回去
We can be back before Soos even realizes we were gone.
天哪  那个时间机器
Oh, no! The timey thing.
摔坏了
It's busted.
你能修好它吗
Can you fix it?
也许吧  我需要一些工具
Maybe. I'll need some tools.
而且我觉得我知道该从哪儿弄到工具
And I think I know where to get some.
神秘小屋
1英里
保持低调
Let's try to lay low.
最好不要改变未来
We don't want to change the future.
或者引发未来
Or <i>cause</i> the future.
我忘了这里面是什么原理了
I forget how this works exactly.
哇  十年前
Wow, 10 years in the past.
一切都既熟悉又新鲜
Everything is samey but also differenty.
好耶
Yeah!
注意啦百老汇  我来啦
Look out Broadway, here I come.
你的梦想不会实现哒  托比
This dream goes nowhere, Toby!
唉  真该死
Aww, marbles.
抱歉
Whoa. Oops. Sorry.
我朋友觉得你很可爱
My friend thinks you're cute.
天呀  谭布丽  闭嘴
Oh, my gosh. Tambry, shut up.
嘿
Ow! Hey!
谢谢
Thank you.
我是说你实在太小了  这样会有点怪
I mean you're super young, so this is weird.
现在你理解她的感受了吧  怪胎
Now you know how <i>she</i> feels, creep.
是啊  我
Yeah, I... Huh.
再稍等一会儿  女士们先生们
Schlep right up, ladies and gentlemen,
马上你们就能看到我最新的陈列品
to see my latest attraction.
好了  畅通无阻
All right, the coast is clear.
我们的机会来了
Now is our chance.
哈  找到了
Ha! Bingo!
好嘞  让我看看
All right, let's see.
来吧  糖果
Aw, come on, candy.
掉下来  快掉下来
Fall. Fall.
让我来
Allow me.
你需要内部人士的帮忙
You just need to know a guy on the inside.
拿到喽
Jackpot!
谢谢  伙计
Thanks, dawg.
你一定是个天才
You must be some kind of genius.
完成了  我想应该已经修好了
All right, I think I've got this thing working
迪普  迪普  快看
Dipper, Dipper, look.
不是吧
No way.
小家伙  你又到处乱跑了
Mi precioso, you keep wandering off.
你可别错过你的大日子哟
You don't want to be late for your big day.
抱歉  奶奶
Sorry, Abuelita.
大日子
Big day?
可能就是在这个生日发生了让他失落的事
This could be the birthday where that personal biz went down.
我们终于可以弄清苏斯讨厌过生日的原因了
We could finally find out why Soos hates his birthday.
好吧  不过我们要快
All right, but let's be quick.
我想要一块生日蛋糕
I want a piece of birthday cake!
谁是英俊的生日男孩呢
Who's a handsome birthday boy?
是你呢
It's you!
苏斯  你这么招姑娘喜欢啊
Soos, you are such a ladies' man.
奶奶  她们可是我的表姐  那样说不好
They're my cousins, Grandma. Gross.
我给你做了个赛车蛋糕
I got you a race car cake.
我还是不明白苏斯为什么会讨厌他的生日
Man, I don't know why Soos hates his birthdays.
看起来挺好的啊
This looks great.
抱歉  哥们儿  你能换个地方坐吗
Sorry, dude, but could you move seats?
那是上宾的位置
That's the seat of honor.
给谁坐的
Uh, who's it for?
唔  实际上是给我爸爸坐的
Oh. Heh. It's for my dad, actually.
我差不多有八年没见过他了  不过他今天会来
I haven't seen him in, like, 8 years, but he's coming today.
一定是他到了
That must be him!
听好了  苏斯  今天是个重要的日子
All right, Soos, today's the big day.
保持冷静  保持冷静
Be cool. Be cool.
这明信片是给
Postcard for...
苏斯的
Soos.
对不起小伙子  今年没法遵守约定了
"Sorry Champ, Couldn't make it this year.
还是太忙了
Real busy again.
明年一定来看你  爸爸
See you next year for sure. Dad."
嘿  没关系的  老弟
Hey, don't sweat it, cuz.
明年你就能见到他了
You'll see him next year.
呵呵  明年
Ha. Yeah, next year.
我要去躺一会儿
I'm gonna go lay down.
不参加派对了
You party without me, dudes.
等等  你还没看礼物呢
Wait, what about your presents?
原来那就是苏斯讨厌生日的原因
So that's why Soos hates his birthday.
在这一天他意识到他的爸爸永远不会回来
It's the day he realized his dad wasn't coming back.
那要开多少派对才能弥补得了呢
So how much partying can fix that?
呆瓜们
Dorks.
少侠罗比
Young Robbie.
苏斯的父亲真是过分
Ay, Soos' father is a dead-beat.
如果他敢在这儿露面，我非撕了他不可！
苏斯  我给你做了恐龙饼干
Soos, I made you cookies shaped like dinosaurs.
我不想要饼干
I don't want cookies.
我只想再见一见爸爸
I want to see Dad again.
他也很想见你
And he wants to see you.
他只是有些  忙
He's just...busy.
在新奥尔良忙吗
Busy in New Orleans?
对啊
Ay. Yes.
相信我  总有一天你会好起来的
Trust me, you will feel better one day.
太糟糕了
Ohh, this is awful.
我们答应给苏斯过一个快乐生日的
We promised Soos a happy birthday,
可是我们现在怎么做得到呢
but how can we give him that now?
我们所知的任何方式都没办法弥补这种伤痛
This goes beyond anything we know how to fix.
-这边  -梅宝  快躲起来
- This way! - Mabel, hide!
他们一定在这附近的什么地方
They've got to be around here somewhere.
我好像听到他们的声音了
I think I heard them!
不许动
Freeze!
跟踪他们的空间信息
Trace their chrono-signatures.
天哪  越早在晶球大战中打败他们
Man, the sooner I defeat those kids in Globnar,
我就能越早赢得时光之愿
the sooner I can win my time wish.
跟你讲讲我的时光之愿好了
Tell you what I'd do if I had a time wish.
早点退休  多花点时间陪孩子
Retire early, spend more time with the kids.
啥啥啥啥陪孩子
Nyah-nyah-nyah-nyah with the kids?!
你不知道时光之愿是无所不能的吗
Don't you know a time wish can literally do anything?
就这么轻轻松松地解决任何无解问题
Any impossible problem solved, just like that.
我是说  你想象一下所有的可能
I mean, imagine the possibilities.
等等  梅宝  就这个  时光之愿
Wait, Mabel, that's it, the time wish.
如果我们在太空大战中打败了布伦丁
If we defeat Blendin in that space battle--
那我们能就能许愿
Then we can wish
让苏斯的爸爸参加苏斯的十二岁生日派对
that Soos' dad came to his 12th birthday.
那苏斯的生日就会永远快乐下去
And Soos' birthdays would be fixed forever--
所有的生日
All of them!
可是你真觉得我们能赢下晶球大战吗
But do you really think we can win Globnar?
这是我们唯一的机会了
It's the only chance we have.
而且  这是为了苏斯
Besides, it's for Soos.
换作他也会为我们这样做的
He would do the same for us.
我们在这儿  布伦丁  我们投降了
Here we are, Blendin. We surrender.
是他们
It's them!
不许动
Freeze!
小心  他们来自过去
Careful, they're from the past.
他们可能有撒粉枪或者啪啪圈
They might have powder muskets or slap bracelets.
听着  各位  这次我们不耍花招了
Look, guys, no tricks this time.
我们准备好应战了  好吗
We're ready to challenge you, okay?
太好了  让晶球大战开始吧
Yes! Let the Globnar begin.
准备参加晶球大战吧
Prepare for Globnar!!!
我居然可以把他静音诶
Hey, turns out I can mute him.
伙计  早点知道该多好
Man, I wish we'd known that earlier.
程序初始化
Initializing.
晶球大战  晶球大战  晶球大战  晶球大战
Globnar! Globnar! Globnar! Globnar!
肃静
Silence!
喔  来吧
Whoo! Oh, yeah!
这娃有点大啊
That is one big baby.
欢迎  晶球大战的贡品们
Welcome, Globnar tributes.
我还有个重要的觉要睡
I have a very important nap to get to,
所以咱们长话短说
so let's make this quick.
你们每人有一次机会在角斗中向仇敌复仇
You each have a chance to settle your time-feud through gladiatorial combat.
在时光宝宝喝完小时瓶里的宇宙沙前
You will have until time baby finishes drinking
你们要完成自己的复仇
the cosmic sand in this hourglass.
不要嘛
No!
来吧  喝沙沙长高高
Come on. It's good for you.
准备好  孩子们
Get ready, kids.
等我得到了时光之愿  你们会恨不得自己赶紧消失
When I get that time wish, you'll wish you were never born.
或者这么说  你们会希望你们还能留下
Or rather, you'll wish you were born,
因为我要许愿让你们彻底消失
because I'm gonna wish you were never born!
做你的美梦去吧  我们可有两个人呢
Dream on! There's two of us.
而且我们还有头发
And we have hair!
喔  喔  是吗
Oh--oh, yeah?
我可是练过的
Well, I have training!
你们以为我在监狱里都做些什么
What do you think I did in prison all that time?
不好
Uh-oh.
晶球大战正式开始
Let the Globnar begin!
太好了
Yeah!
晶球大战
Globnar!
很好
Very good.
你们已经摆脱了轮回时钟兽
You have escaped the Cyclocks.
太好了  布伦丁胜利在望
Yes! Blendin for the almost-win!
接下来是晶球大战的终极挑战
There is only one final challenge for Globnar.
一个古老的游戏  有数千年历史
An ancient game, thousands of years old,
因其出众的纯策略性而被选中
chosen for its exemplification of pure strategy.
古老的激光枪战艺术
The ancient art of laser tag!
第一个碰到胜利之球的人即是赢家
The one who touches the victory orb first will win.
激光枪战  真的吗
Laser tag? Seriously?
它现在看起来的确很简单
Oh, I know it doesn't seem that challenging now,
但造雾机打开以后  有你们好看的
but just wait until they turn on that fog machine.
你们就完了
You'll be done for.
你们就乖乖等着
You just wait until you--
打中了
Hit.
打中了  打中了  打中了  打中了
Hit, hit, hit, hit.
我的天哪
Oh, man.
梅宝  快碰胜者球
Mabel, grab the orb!
好嘞
Got it.
战斗结束
It is finished!
不
No!
-不  不  -太好了
- No! No! - Yes!
你们已经在晶球大战中胜出
You have made victory in Globnar.
在我实现你的时光之愿前
Before I give you your time wish,
告诉我们  你们打算怎么处置失败者
tell us what fate do you decide for the loser?
哦  天哪
Oh, jeez.
让他死
Death!
-梅宝  -抱歉
- Mabel. - Sorry.
有点被冲昏头脑了
Got carried away.
布伦丁的确是想让我们彻底消失来着
So Blendin did try to wish us out of existence,
但毁了他的生活也是我们的过错
but it was kind of our fault for ruining his life.
是啊  就他这惨样也坏不到哪儿去
Yeah, and he's kind of too sad to be a real bad guy.
也许我们现在对他好点
Maybe if we treat him right in the present,
他在将来至少能好过一些
he'll turn out better in the future.
好的  只要你时刻留意着他
Okay, as long as you keep an eye on him,
我们希望放走布伦丁
we'd like to set Blendin free
并且恢复他在时光异常校正队的职位
and restore his position at the Time Anomaly Correction Unit.
再给他一头漂亮的头发
And give him pretty hair.
没问题
So be it.
什么  你们愿意这样对我
What? You'd do that for me?
我恢复原职了
I got my job back!
真想找个人抱抱
I feel like hugging somebody.
我能用八种方法搞死你
I can kill you in eight different ways.
好的  长官
Yes, sir.
那么  孩子们  你们想用时光之愿得到什么
Now, children, what is it that you want for your time wish?
谢谢你  但这愿望不是许给我们的
Thank you, but the wish isn't for us.
不是你们吗
Not you?
那是谁啊
But then who?
还有谁值得获取如此强大的力量
Who is worthy to receive such power?
迪普  梅宝
Dipper? Mabel?
唉  我这是干嘛呢
Ah, who am I kidding?
我还没准备好面对这些
I'm not up for this.
正面就留下来
Heads, I stay.
反面就去给自己做点恐龙形状的饼干
Tails, I go make myself some dinosaur shaped cookies.
呵  这倒是挺新奇的
Huh. That's unconventional.
-苏斯  -伙计们
- Soos! - Guys!
真抱歉让你久等了  伙计
We're so sorry we left you hanging, dude.
我们被困在这时间旅行的东西里了
We got caught up in this time travel junk.
而且还有个轮回时钟兽
And there was a time Cyclops.
别忘了还有时光赛车
And don't forget about the time race.
但重点是  苏斯
But the point is, Soos,
我们也许能还你个快乐的生日了
we think we know how to fix your birthday.
哇  真的吗
Whoa. Really?
等一下  你们这么铤而走险都是为了我吗
Wait, you guys did all of that for me?
而且不仅如此
And that's not all.
这是你的时光之愿
Behold your time wish,
无悖论限制  自由操控时间的能力
the power to alter time, paradox-free, in any way you choose.
我们觉得唯一一件
We think the only thing
能让你开心起来的事情就是见到你爸
that can make you happy is meeting your dad.
但是选择权在你手里
But the choice is yours.
我只要碰一下这东西  就能见到爸爸吗
You mean, I can finally see my dad by touching this thing?
你们俩在时空中混战
And you guys battled through time and space
就是为了给我这个吗
just to get this for me?
你还等什么呢  苏斯
What are you waiting for, Soos?
好吧  没什么大不了的
All right. Here goes nothing.
-等等  等等  -搞什么
- Wait, what? - What the...
嘭  你们恢复啦  好好享受吧
Bam! Fixed you up. Enjoy, dudes!
可是  苏斯  你不想见到爸爸吗
But, Soos, what about meeting your dad?
生日应该是跟关心自己的人一起过
Well, birthdays are supposed to be spent with the people who care about you.
但你猜怎么着
But you know what?
那个人甚至都懒得来见我一面
That dude didn't care about me enough to visit me once,
更别说是像你们这样为我上刀山下火海了
let alone fight monsters through time and space like you dudes.
你们为了让我开心  可是连角斗都参加了
I mean, you had a gladiator fight just to make me happy.
我一直以来真是太不可理喻了
I've been being ridiculous this whole time.
不管我的爸爸是谁  他都要靠边站了
Whoever my dad was, he could take a hike.
我知道自己的家人是谁了  就是你们啊
I know who my family is now, and it's you dudes.
谢谢你们给了我最好的生日
Thanks for giving me the best birthday ever.
你在逗我吗
Are you kidding me?!
你知道自己刚才浪费了什么吗
Do you have any idea what you've just wasted?
你知道有多少人为得到时光之愿而付出了生命吗
Do you know how many have died to get a time wish?
还有那些因此发动的战争
The wars that were started?
我的愿望可不止这些
That's not all, dudes.
我还要了块吃不完的披萨
I also wished for the slice of infinite pizza.
看好了
Watch.
而且它能这样  永远不停地复原
And it can do that for, like, infinity.
太好了  这才是好的时光之愿
Phew! That's a good time wish.
离激光枪战结束还有十分钟
There's still 10 minutes before laser tag closes.
你们还想再玩会儿吗
You dudes want to play?
好耶
Yeah.
生日快乐  苏斯
Happy birthday, Soos.
哇  我好像听到了爆炸的声音
Whoa. Thought I heard an explosion.
哇  那是啥
Whoa, what's this?
神秘小屋
Mystery Shack?
到此为止了
That is it!
你是个烂得独一无二的零工
You are single-handedly the worst handyman I've ever seen.
呃  嗨  打扰了  先生
Uh, hey, excuse me, sir.
嗨  小孩儿  你会不会修高尔夫球车啊
Hey you, gumdrop, think you can fix a golf cart?
我也不太确定自己
Well, I don't know if I--
好了  你被雇用了
Boom, you're hired.
这衣服均码
One size fits all.
快到神秘小屋里来转转吧  伙计们
Step right up to the Mystery Shack, folks.
快进来看看
Step right up.